As you learn Python throughout this course,
بينما تتعلم لغة Python أثناء دراستك لهذه الدورة،
there are a few things you should keep in mind.
هناك بعض الأمور التي ينبغي لك أن تتذكرها.
First, unlike languages like SQL,
أولاً، على عكس لغات أخرى مثل SQL،
Python is case sensitive,
فإن لغة Python حساسة لحالة الحرف اللاتيني،
meaning these two words mean two different things.
أي أن هاتين الكلمتين لهما معنيان مختلفان.
Second, spacing is important in Python.
ثانياً، ترك المسافات مهم في لغة Python.
Since it isn't very heavy on syntax like other languages,
بما أنها لا تحتوي على الكثير من بناءات الجُمل كما في اللغات الأخرى،
it relies a lot on spacing,
فهي تعتمد كثيراً على مباعدة الكلمات والسطور،
which can be confusing at first,
وهو ما قد يكون مربكاً في البداية،
but really nice and clean when you get the hang of it.
لكن تعلمه يجعل الأمر سلساً ومرتباً.
Third, there will be times you get errors in this course.
ثالثاً، أحياناً ستظهر لك رسائل وجود أخطاء في تعليماتك البرمجية في هذه الدورة.
Keep in mind, errors don't make you a bad programmer.
تذكر أن الأخطاء لا تجعل منك مبرمجاً سيئاً،
It's just a computer telling you it doesn't understand.
إنما هي طريقة الحاسوب في إخبارك بأنه لم يفهم.
Use error messages to help you learn how to write code
استخدم رسائل الأخطاء لتعلم كيفية كتابة تعليمات برمجية
that can be interpreted the way you wish. Let's get started.
يمكن ترجمتها بالطريقة التي تبتغيها. لنبدأ.